Guide to the Phoebe Jacobs Jazz collection,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Phoebe Jacobs Jazz collection,
1951-2002
Jacobs, Phoebe, collector.
11 linear ft. 2,500 items in (23 boxes; 1 Flat Box; 1 Scroll Box).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY. 10027
5420059
Biographical Note
Public relations executive; Director public relation for The Rainbow Room, 1969-1973; Vice President of the Louis Armstrong Educational Foundation, 1970. Sy Kravitz has written 'The life and career of Phoebe Jacobs reads like a who's who of the country's greatest jazz musicians and singers with whom she has worked.' Executive vice president of the Louis Armstrong Educational Foundation, she has made invaluable contributions to Armstrong's living legacy, playing an important role in the establishment of the Armstrong Archives at Queens College in New York in 1993. In 1995, her long campaign for the release of a Louis Armstrong postal stamp came to fruition. She is a member of the Advisory Council for Lincoln Center's The Ellington Centennial and Research Associate in the jazz program at the Museum of American History.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, articles, documents, photographs, posters, clippings relating to the professional career of Phoebe Jacobs and notable jazz musicians, especially Louis Armstrong.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 6 series:
Series I: Correspondence
Series II: Pheobe Jacobs Personal Material
Series III: Jazz Musicians
Series IV: Publicity Material
Series V: Promotional Materials
Series VI: Miscellaneous
Subjects
Louis Armstrong Educational Foundation.; Armstrong, Louis, 1901-1971.; Blake, Eubie, 1887-1983.; Ellington, Duke, 1899-1974.; Ellington, Mercer.; Ellington, Mercedes.; Fitzgerald, Ella.; Gillespie, Dizzy, 1917-1993.; Goodman, Benny, 1909-1986.; Lee, Peggy, 1920-2002.; Marsalis, Wynton, 1961-; Oliver, Sy.; Vaughan, Sarah, 1924-1990.; African American composers.; African American musicians.; African American singers.; Jazz--History.; Jazz musicians.; Music publicity.; Correspondence; Manuscripts; Photographs
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located on-site.
Acquisition
Phoebe Jacobs Gift 2002 and 2004.
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Subseries I.1: Cataloged Correspondence
    - Bennet, Tony and Bernadette To Phoebe Jacobs, [n.p.], 1992/1997, 1992; 1997, (1 card s. 1 card ) (Box 7, Folder 155)
      [Christmas cards]
    - Bruce, Lenny To Phoebe Jacobs, New York, [n.d.], (1 a.l.s. ) (Box 7, Folder 156)
    - Fitzgerald, Ella To Phoebe Jacobs, Paris, 23 March 1963, (1 a.pc.s. ) (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Fitzgerald, Ella To Phoebe Jacobs, Paris, 12 May 1963, (1 telegram ) (Box 7, Folder 158)
    - Fitzgerald, Ella To Phoebe Jacobs, Beverly Hills, CA, 7 Jan 1992, (1 a.l.s. ) (Box 7, Folder 159)
      [Thank you card]
    - Fitzgerald To Phoebe Jacobs, New York, 10 April 1980, (1 a.l.s. ) (Box 7, Folder 160)
      [From Arlie Small, Ella Fitzgerald's cousin and traveling companion]
    - Goodman, Benny To Phoebe Jacobs; with separate graphics featuring likeness of Goodman, Basin Street East: New York, 13 May 1963, (1 note card 3 graphics 1, cocktail napkin ) (Box 7, Folder 161)
      [Event featuring the debut of Barbara Streisand]
    - Goodman, Benny To Phoebe Jacobs, New York, 21 August 1974; 10 March 1975, (2 a.l.s. 2 postmarked envelope ) (Box 7, Folder 162)
      [Thank you card for gift]
    - Goodman, Benny To Phoebe Jacobs, New York, 2 July 1975, (1 a.l.s. 1 postmarked envelope ) (Box 7, Folder 163)
    - Goodman, Benny To Phoebe Jacobs, New York, 8 December 1975, (1 a.l.s. ) (Box 7, Folder 164)
    - Goodman, Benny To Phoebe Jacobs, New York, 29 April 1979, (2 announcements ) (Box 7, Folder 165)
      [Announcement of memorial service for Benny Goodman]
    - Goodman, Benny To Phoebe Jacobs, New York, [n.d.] & 1978, (3 a.l.s. 1 t.l. 1, postmarked envelope ) (Box 7, Folder 166)
      [Miscellaneous undated birthday and Christmas cards; invite to Carnegie Hall concert]
    - Lee, Peggy To Phoebe Jacobs, New York, 18 January 1961, (1 t.l. 2 a.n.s. 1, envelope ) (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Lee, Peggy To Phoebe Jacobs, California, 12 December 1961, (1 p.c.s. ) (Box 7, Folder 168)
    - Lee, Peggy To Phoebe Jacobs, Los Angeles, CA, 28 August 1967, (1 t.l.s. 1 postmarked envelope ) (Box 7, Folder 169)
    - Lee, Peggy To Phoebe [and Lou] Jacobs, New York, 25 October 1968, (1 t.l.s. 1 postmarked envelope ) (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Lee, Peggy To Phoebe Jacobs, New York, 9 June 1969, (1 t.ls. 1 envelope ) (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Lee, Peggy To Phoebe Jacobs, CA, 8 December 1971, (1 t.ls. 1 postmarked envelope ) (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Lee, Peggy To Phoebe Jacobs, Los Angeles, CA, 19 December 1972, (1 t.l.s. 1 postmarked envelope ) (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Lee, Peggy To Phoebe Jacobs, [n.p.], 15 May 1991, (1 t.l.s. ) (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Lee, Peggy To Phoebe Jacobs, [n.p.], 10 June 1992, (1 a.l.s. ) (Box 7, Folder 15)
      [With attached newspaper clippings]
    - Lee, Peggy To Phoebe Jacobs, New York, 28 October 1997, (2 pages t.l.s. ) (Box 7, Folder 16)
      [One page letter from Jane (on Peggy Lee's personal stationary) enclosing Lee's favorite fan letter]
    - Lee, Peggy To Phoebe Jacobs, [n.p.], [n.d.], (7 a.l.s. 1 t.l. ) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Lewis, Jerry To Phoebe Jacobs, New York, 13 August 1970, (1 page t.l.s. 2 place sitting cards 1, postmarked envelope ) (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Lewis, Jerry To Phoebe Jacobs, New York, 31 August 1970, (1 page t.l. 1 postmarked envelope ) (Box 7, Folder 19)
      [Noted "Dictated but not read"]
    - Nixon, Richard To Duke Ellington, Washington D.C., 2 November 1971, (1 page photocopy ) (Box 7, Folder 180)
    - Vaughn, Sarah To Phoebe Jacobs, California, 1960; 1974, (1 card a.ms.s. 1 ) (Box 7, Folder 181)
    - Vaughn, Sarah To Phoebe Jacobs, CA, 23 December 1974, (1 card a.ms.s. 1 postmarked envelope 1, clipping ) (Box 7, Folder 182)
      [Newspaper clipping includes photographs of Frank Reynolds and Ella Fitzgerald.]
    - Miscellaneous unidentified letters, [n.p.], (1 folder ) (Box 7, Folder 184)
      [1 of 2 folders]
    - Miscellaneous unidentified letters, [n.p.], (1 folder ) (Box 7, Folder 185)
      [1of 2 folders]
    - To Mrs. Dent, New York, 1998, (1 folder ) (Box 7, Folder 186)
      [Thank you letters from a grade school class]
  - Subseries I.2: Arranged Correspondence
    - Assorted correspondence to and from Phoebe Jacobs and the Louis Armstrong Educational Foundation. Includes proposals for joint projects with other cultural institutions, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 folder ) (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Correspondents Abellana through Gressley, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 box ) (Box 8)
    - Correspondents Hall through Price (H-P), [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 box ) (Box 9)
    - Correspondents Ramos through York (Q-Z), [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 box ) (Box 10)
  - Subseries I.3: Personal
    - Bergreen, Laurence To Phoebe Jacobs, New York, 9 June 1997, (1 page t.l.s. ) (Box 3, Folder 66)
      [Author of Louis Armstrong biography.]
    - Blake, Marion To Phoebe Jacobs, Brooklyn, NY, 19 January 1981, (1 page a.l.s. 1 page photocopy ) (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Bolcom, William and Joan Morris To Phoebe Jacobs, Ann Arbor, Michigan, 14 August 1998, (1 page a.l.s. ) (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Brown, Crystal To Phoebe Jacobs, New York, 12 December 1996, (4 pages a.l.s. ) (Box 3, Folder 69)
      [Note and heartrending "Life Story, Part 1" addressed to Phoebe Jacobs.]
    - Cunningham, Evelyn State of New York, Executive Chamber To Phoebe Jacobs, New York, 16 August 1971, (1 page ) (Box 3, Folder 70)
      [With postmarked envelope. Thank you letter for Ellington party.]
    - [Crouch] Niz To Phoebe Jacobs, [n.p.], 9 June 1997, (1 card a.l.s. ) (Box 3, Folder 71)
      [Wife of Stanley Crouch. Thank you card.]
    - Edelson, Rachel To Phoebe Jacobs, Sacramento, California, 11 August 1997, (1 page a.l.s. ) (Box 3, Folder 74)
      [Daughter of Benny Goodman.]
    - Ellington, Mercedes To Phoebe Jacobs, [n.p.], 21 September [n.y.], (1 a.l.s. ) (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Gibson, Rob Jazz at Lincoln Center To Phoebe Jacobs, [n.p.], 23 January 1995 (Box 3, Folder 73)
      [Thank you card.]
    - Haygood, Will To Phoebe Jacobs, Cambridge, MA, 27 July 1998, (1 page t.l.s. ) (Box 3, Folder 75)
      [From writer of biography on Sammy Davis Jr.]
    - Hendricks To Phoebe Jacobs, Mill Valley, CA, 22 January 1973, (2 page t.l.s. ) (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Jacobs, Phoebe To E. Lisk Wyckoff of Trubin Sillcocks Edelman & Knapp, [n.p.], 30 June [n.y.], (1 page t.ms. ) (Box 3, Folder 87)
      [Handwritten note indicates letter was never sent. ]
    - Lee, Peggy To Phoebe and Lou Jacobs, [n.p.], 10 May 1986, (1 t.l.s. 1 envelope postmarked ) (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Nicki [Lee] To Phoebe Jacobs, Arizona, 20 July 1996, (1 a.l.s. ) (Box 3, Folder 78)
      [From Peggy Lee's daughter with references to Peggy Lee.]
    - Marsalis,Wynton To Phoebe Jacobs, Wynton Marsalis Enterprises, New York, 6 January 1995, (1 t.l.s. ) (Box 3, Folder 79)
      [Seasonal greetings.]
    - Orgill, Roxane To Phoebe Jacobs, [n.p.], 24 October 1997, (1 a.p.c.s. ) (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Rivers, Mavis To Phoebe Jacobs, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 pages a.l.s. ) (Box 3, Folder 81)
      [Jacobs' note: "Worked with Red Norid."]
    - Samuels, Roslyn To Phoebe Jacobs, California, 2 February 1998, (1 a.l.s. 1 postmarked envelope ) (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Shackman, Beverly To Shackman from Phoebe Jacobs, New York, 23 1995, (1 page photocopy ) (Box 3, Folder 83)
      [Copy of handwritten letter regarding necklace inheritance.]
    - Shorin, Iris Jazz Foundation of America To Phoebe Jacobs, New York, 12 February 1992, (1 page t.l.s. ) (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Storfer, Herb Jazz Foundation of America To Herb Storfer from Phoebe Jacobs, New York, 27 January 1992, (1 t.l.s. ) (Box 3, Folder 84)
      [Jacobs announces resignation from Jazz Foundation of America.]
    - Wyckoff, E. Lisk Trubin Sillcocks Edelman & Knapp To Phoebe Jacobs, New York NY, 1976-1979, (3 pages t.ms.s. ) (Box 3, Folder 86)
      [Legal correspondence regarding Estate of Eve Ellis.]
    - Open letter with memories of Eubie Blake; copy of mailgram inviting Blake to the White House dinner where he received the Presidential Medal of Freedom., [v.p.], [n.d.], (9 pages t.ms. ) (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - To Phoebe Jacobs. Miscellaneous correspondence, [v.p.], [n.d.]; 1977-2000, (1 folder ) (Box 3, Folder 89)
      [Handwritten, typewritten, and photocopied letters.]
- Series II: Pheobe Jacobs Personal Material
  - Subseries II.1: General
    - Manuscript of autobiography., [n.d.], (121 pages t.ms. 1 t.ms. ) (Box 1, Folder 1)
      [With annotations by Armstrong handwritten in green ink. Title changes from "Life Story of Louis Armstrong"to "The Armstrong Story." ]
    - Assorted correspondence, press clippings, contracts regarding the work of Phoebe Jacobs., [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 folder ) (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - Jacobs, Phoebe Resume, Scarsdale, NY, Through Feb. 1957, (1 page t.ms. ) (Box 11, Folder 187)
    - New York Jazz Museum List of inventory and staff responsibilities, New York, April 1978, (2 pages t.ms. 1 postmarked envelope. ) (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - Jacobs, Phoebe Vita through 1981, [v.p.], 1981, (1 page t.ms. ) (Box 11, Folder 188)
    - Gerald Marks Materials related to the life and career of Gerald Marks, composer. Includes press biographies and press releases, newspaper articles, correspondence with Phil Leshin (Marks' manager and publicist), and Mr. Marks' will, Vita, clippings, last will and testament, [n.p.], [n.d.] 1991-1997, (1 folder ) (Box 5, Folder 110)
      [Phoebe Jacobs named among beneficiaries in will.]
    - Jacobs, Phoebe Interview by James Briggs Murray, New York, 11 September 1996, (22 pages t.ms. ) (Box 11, Folder 189)
      [Transcribed by Frankie MacCormick.]
    - Social paraphrenalia: invitations, funeral announcement, unused picture postcards, press releases, receipts., [n.p.], [n.d.]; 1980-1999, (1 folder ) (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Jacobs, Phoebe ABC Radio Biographical write up, New York, 20 April 1998, (1 page t.ms. facsimile ) (Box 11, Folder 190)
      [With handwritten changes (possibly by Jacobs)]
    - Phoebe Jacobs promotional items, [n.p.], [n.d.] 1994, (1 folder ) (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Jacobs, Phoebe A brief biography, New York, 28 June 2001, (1page ) (Box 11, Folder 191)
      [From the fax machine of Phil Leshin]
    - Historical information and maps re: College Point, Central Park, The Bronx Zoo and other New York Locales, New York, [n.d.], (1 folder ) (Box 11, Folder 194)
      [Extensive information on Central Park and Bronx Zoo. ]
    - U.S. Open Complimentary tickets: Phoebe Jacobs and guest, New York, August 1999, (2 invitations 1 postmarked envelope 1, business card ) (Box 11, Folder 199)
    - High School for Leadership To Phoebe Jacobs, New York, [n.d.], (1 a.l.s. ) (Box 11, Folder 200)
      [Thank you for support of music department]
    - Jacobs, Phoebe Miscellaneous receipts and billing records, [n.p.], 2000-2002, (4 items ) (Box 11, Folder 201)
    - Invitations, [n.p.] Monaco; New York, [n.d.]; 1962-1974, (5 items ) (Box 11, Folder 202)
    - Jacobs, Phoebe Ticket stub and travel itinerary for Lucille Armstrong and Phoebe Jacobs, [v.p.] New York, Italy, Warsaw, 1974, (2 items ) (Box 11, Folder 204)
    - Miscellaneous items from the postal service, [n.p.], [n.d.] 1982, (4 items ) (Box 11, Folder 205)
    - Miscellaneous notepaper and printed materials, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 folder ) (Box 11, Folder 206)
    - Miscellaneous personal items, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 folder ) (Box 11, Folder 207)
      [Envelope marked "Louis and Lucille's marriage license" empty]
    - Paraphernalia regarding Phoebe Jacobs' activities: handwritten notes, playbills, expenses, invitations, etc. (Box 3, Folder 36)
      [Includes undated, signed New Year's note to Jacobs from Mercer Ellington.]
    - Assorted correspondence to and from Ms. Phoebe Jacobs, mostly regarding jazz promotion, events, and concerts, [v.p.], [n.d.] 1980-1999, (1 folder ) (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Schuyler, George S. Black No More, New York, July 1999, (1v. Advance Uncorrected Proof ) (Box 19)
      [Signed by Phoebe Jacobs]
    - Various Magazines and Printed Material, (14 items ) (Box 19)
      [Some magazines contain articles pertaining to Louis Armstrong]
    - Miscellaneous memorabilia (Box 23)
      [Items include daily planners for 1983, 1994 and note pad from Lucille Armstrong 1974 trip]
  - Subseries II.2: Rainbow Room
    - Rainbow Room Invitations to parties held at Rainbow Room and resturant revues, New York City (Box 11, Folder 192)
    - Rainbow Room Press materials and clippings regarding Phoebe Jacob's publicity position at the venue, New York, [n.d.] 1968, (1 folder ) (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - Rainbow Room Items regarding entertainment at the Rainbow Room, New York, [n.d.] 1970-1971, (10 items ) (Box 11, Folder 193)
      [Where Phoebe Jacobs was public relations assistant. One event "The British are Coming!" noted specifically as her creation.]
- Series III: Jazz Musicians
  Includes manuscripts
  - Subseries III.1: Louis Armstrong
    - Sub-subseries III.1.1: General Files
      - Louis Armstrong Beth Israel hospital story in another person's hand (transcribed) Collections of Song Lyrics written in Louis Armstrong's hand, June 23, 1971, (11 pages photocopies ) (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Autobiography titled "Our Neighborhood"; 8 copies of 6 pages, [n.p.], [n.d.], (48pages ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
        [Photocopies of originals written in Armstrong's hand.]
      - Autobiography: 2 copies of pages numbered to 77, some missing, Sunday, March 15, 1970 & June 1st, 1970, ( 154 pages ) (Box 1, Folder 4)
        [Photocopies of originals in Armstrong's hand.]
      - Avakian, George To Joe Moore., Columbia Records, 25 April 1956, (1 page t.ms. ) (Box 1, Folder 20)
        [Unsigned copy. Regarding upcoming Armstrong recording.]
      - Louis Armstrong Autobiography: "Louis Armstrong and the Jewish Family in New Orleans, LA. The Year of 1907, manuscript with drafts, Beth Israel Hospital, NY, 31 March 1969, (6 page t.ms. 48 pages copies ) (Box 1, Folder 5)
        [Pages in incomplete numerical order; photocopies contain duplicates]
      - Avakian, George Columbia Records To Joe Glaser., [n.p.], 13 June 1956 (Box 1, Folder 21)
        [Unsigned copy. Correspondence regarding copyrights, royalties, and release of "The Faithful Hussar" and "Six Foot Four."]
      - Avakian, George Columbia Records To Joe Glaser, [n.p.], 14 June 1956, (1 page t.ms. ) (Box 1, Folder 22)
        [Unsigned copy. List of Armstrong records produced by Columbia Records.]
      - Louis Armstrong Lists of song titles for performances and recordings, [v.p.], 1952-1957, (5pages 5 pages ) (Box 1, Folder 6)
        [Photocopies of original written in Armstrong's hand.]
      - Louis Armstrong To: Joe Glaser (Armstrong's manager). Contains commentary (liner notes) on various compositions; 5 copies of 9 pages, Los Angeles, CA., May 22, 1951., (45 pages t.ms. ) (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Louis Armstrong Autobiography titled "New Orleans." 2 copies of 42 pages, May 6, 1968, (84 pages copies ) (Box 1, Folder 8)
        [Photocopies of original ms. in Armstrong's hand. Memoir inspired by letter from childhood friend: Larry Amadee of Chicago, IL.]
      - Louis Armstrong To: Joe Glaser, Louis Armstrong's manager. [v.p.], [n.d.] 1954-1960, (75 pages photocopies ) (Box 1, Folder 9)
        [Included are typed and handwritten letters, telegrams, and copies of the mailing envelopes.. Many typed on assorted hotel stationary while on tour. Also included is a photocopy of "Lose Weight the Satchmo Way" and two pages of "The Armstrong Story" numbered pages 167-168 with a note written to Glaser.]
      - Louis Armstrong Autobiography: 3 copies of pages 20-54, printed two to a page. [n.d.], (54 pages photocopies ) (Box 1, Folder 10)
        [Photocopies of originals written in Armstrong's hand. Content includes courtship and marriage between Armstrong and last wife Lucille.]
      - Louis Armstrong Autobiography: work titled "Barbershop"; 2 copies of 5 pages, [n.d.], (10 pages copies ) (Box 1, Folder 11)
        [Photocopies of original ms. in Armstrong's hand.]
      - Louis Armstrong Song lyrics "You're in New Orleans," "A Boat that's leaving for New York," "Where's My Bess?", "Oh, Lord-I'm on my way," "Dance to Dixie Land," "Creole Gumbo," "I'm a Red Hot papa," "Surrender"; 3 copies of 9 pages, [n.d.], (18 pages copies ) (Box 1, Folder 12)
        [Photocopies of originals in Armstrong's hand; selections previously sorted together]
      - Louis Armstrong Lyrics: "We Have All the Time in the World"; copies of 1 page original, [n.p.], [n.d.], (8 pages copies ) (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Autobiography: "The Satchmo Story, 2nd Edition." 3 copies of 11 doublesided pages., [n.d.], (18 pages copies ) (Box 1, Folder 14)
        [Copies of original t.ms.]
      - Louis Armstrong Autobiography: "The Armstrong Story"; copies of various segments of larger work. Samples of Armstrong's handwriting., [n.p.], [n.d.], (50 pages copies ) (Box 1, Folder 15)
        [Photocopies of t.ms. and a.ms. by Armstrong, some pages doubled sided.]
      - Avakian, George Columbia Records To Goddard Lieberson. 29 December 1955, (1 page t.ms. ) (Box 1, Folder 17)
        [Unsigned copy. Internal discussion regarding signing Armstrong for a long term exclusive contract. References to Armstrong's manager Joe Glaser.]
      - Avakian, George Columbia Records To Goddard Lieberson, 27 March 1956, (1 page t.ms. ) (Box 1, Folder 18)
        [Irritable interoffice communication referring to copyright issues and personal dealer with Joe Glaser.]
      - Avakian, George To Fred Friendly, Columbia Records, 2 April 1956, (1 page t.ms. ) (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Handwritten memoir numbered 2-22 with extra pages, [n.d.], (24 pages photocopy ) (Box 1, Folder 23)
        [Copies of handwritten manuscript.]
      - Queens Library Foundation "Jazz Programming at East Elmhurst: Fiscal Year 2000 Report": materials submitted to the Louis Armstrong Educational Foundation, New York, March 2000, (1 folder ) (Box 4, Folder 97)
      - Correspondence regarding the Louis Armstrong House and Archives at Queens College, New York, 1994-2000, (1 folder ) (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - Sub-subseries III.1.2: Louis Armstrong Educational Foundation
      - Louis Armstrong Educational Foundation Event listings, press releases and paraphernalia regarding Louis Armstrong House Foundation, New York, [n.d.], (1 folder ) (Box 4, Folder 101)
      - Louis Armstrong Educational Foundation Miscellaneous PR items, New York, [n.d.]; 1998, (1 folder) (Box 12, Folder 209)
      - Louis Armstrong House and Archives Miscellaneous materials include meeting notes, promotional materials, proposals, Queens, New York, [n.d.] 1998-2002, (1 folder ) (Box 12, Folder 211)
      - Louis Armstrong Educational Foundation Projects, proposals, meeting minutes, New York, 1999-2002, (1 folder ) (Box 12, Folder 208)
      - Queens College Envelopes and flyers celebrating the Louis Armstrong Educational Foundation, New York, 24 May 1994, (6envelopes 2 flyers ) (Box 11, Folder 197)
      - Louis Armstrong House and Archives press kit. Sent to the Louis Armstrong Educational Foundation from Michael Cogswell, Director of the Archives at Queens College, New York, 1999-2000, (1 folder ) (Box 4, Folder 100)
      - Jazz Reach A general operating grant request from Jazz Reach presented to the Louis Armstrong Educational Foundation, November 2001 (Box 21)
        [Folder also contains printed material concerning Jazz Reach]
    - Sub-subsubseries III.1.3: Photographs
      - Louis Armstrong Photograph: close head shot, black and white, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 13 1/2 x 9 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Louis Armstrong Profile from the back; on stage; black and white, Time/Life: New York, [n.d.], (1 photograph 13 x 10 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Photographs and picture postcards, [v.p.], [n.d.], (9 items ) (Box 5, Folder 107)
        [Includes three informal snapshots: 1 of Lucille Armstrong; two of dedication of Louis Armstrong stadium (Wynton Marsalis and the Jazz at Lincoln Center big band playing on the field)]
      - Publicity photographs of Louis Armstrong, [n.p.], [n.d.], (9 8 x 10 inch, black and white 2 8 x 10 inch, color 1, 5 1/2 x 8 1/2 inch, black and white ) (Box 12, Folder 220)
        [One photograph with Jack Teagarden]
      - Miscellaneous photographs of Louis Armstrong, [n.p.], [n.d.]; 1931, (5 items ) (Box 12, Folder 222)
        [Includes 8 x 10 black and white of baseball team "Armstrong's Secret Nine, 1931"]
      - Armstrong, Lucille Color photographs, Poland, 1974, (1 5 x 7 inches 1 3 1/4 x 4 1/4 inches ) (Box 18, Folder 358)
        [With Phoebe Jacobs during 1974 tour in Rumania, Czechoslovakia, Hungary, France, and England.]
      - Armstrong, Lucille Color snapshots, New York; Las Vegas, 31 December 1975; [n.d.], (2 3 1/2 x 5 inches 1 3 1/2 x 4 1/4 inches ) (Box 18, Folder 359)
        [With Phoebe Jacobs and Louis Jacobs]
      - Armstrong, Louis Sacred Heart Church Snapshots from "A Music Tribute to Louis Armstrong", New Orleans, 25 August 2000, (11 color photographs ) (Box 12, Folder 219)
        [Pictures of a tribut to Louis Armstrong; No pictures of Louis Armstrong himself]
    - Sub-subsubseries III.1.4: Clippings
      - Newspaper clippings regarding Armstrong life and activities: copies and originals, [v.p.], [n.d.]1995-2002, (1 folder ) (Box 12, Folder 214)
      - Newspaper clippings, [v.p], 1975-1999, (1 folder ) (Box 5, Folder 104)
      - Periodical clippings, [v.p.], [n.d.] 1971-2000, (1 folder ) (Box 5, Folder 105)